hey guys Pastor Myers here I want to
invite you to check out this message on
the state of the Dead uh the doctrine of
Eternal uh uh fire as well as
justification by faith we're tying all
these three subjects in together may God
bless you as you
watch
[Music]
oh
so justification by faith justification
by faith and the doctrine of eternal
torment you you may be asking yourselves
how do these two subjects even connect
and we're going to see that they very
much so connect the first thing that we
that we are going to do and this is a
this is a study today amen this is a
Bible study we're going to be looking at
several verses we're going to be looking
at many verses but we're going to be
touching on some very important key
themes
so the first thing that I want to do is
um let's go to Genesis chapter 15
Genesis chapter 15 and verse 4 Genesis
15 verse4 the Bible says here and behold
the word of
Jehovah came to him
saying this one shall not be your Heir
but he that shall come forth out of your
own bowels shall be your Heir and he
brought him outside and said look now
toward the heaven and count the Stars if
you are able to count them and he said
to him so shall your seed be and he
believed in
Jehovah and he counted it to him for
righteousness okay so what's happening
here is uh uh we are we are looking the
first thing we want to understand is
what is justification by faith and and
the individual to go
to when we're seeking to understand this
theme of justification by faith is
Abraham the Bible says that Abraham
believed God and it was counted to him
for righteousness so we want to ask a
couple simple questions and it is this
first of
all what did Abraham believe what did
Abraham believe well the verse we just
read pointed out that
Abraham was told that he was going to
have a child and this child would be the
heir would would be uh uh the the first
of a huge a large number of
Offspring so we know that Abraham goes
many years without receiving this
without receiving this child but in his
old
age the child is
born what is Abraham believing here
Risha says he believed God's word Clint
says he believed prophecy all very good
answers but I want to point out
something very specific uh Patty says
God's promise let me point out something
very specific here and it is
this that what Abraham believed in was a
miracle birth put that in the chat for
me please put the words in the chat
Miracle birth Abraham believed in a
miracle birth and we understand that
this miracle birth of Isaac was a
foreshadow
of the miracle birth of Jesus so it's
not just that God said anything and
Abraham was like okay I believe that it
was the promise regarding a miraculous
birth what does that signify to us
justification by
faith believing What God Says and and
having be having it being counted for
righteousness revolves around believing
that Jesus
came to this earth to die for our sins
put a one in the chat if that makes
sense so far it is believing in the
miracle birth of Jesus who would come
into this world to justify us so we see
number one Abraham believed in a miracle
birth which was a foreshadow of the
birth of Jesus but there is something
else there is something
else in the book of Hebrews I'm sorry
let's let's stay in the book of Genesis
we're going to go to Genesis 22 and: 11
in Genesis 22:1 the Bible says and the
angel of Jehovah called to him from the
heavens and said Abraham Abraham and he
said here am I now y'all know what's
what what's happening here right why is
the Angel suddenly calling out to
Abraham well it's because Abraham is
about to
sacrifice Isaac listen to what the Bible
says do not lay your hand on the lad nor
do anything to him for now I
know now I know that you fear God since
you have not withheld your son your only
son from me and Abraham lifted up his
eyes and looked and behold a ram behind
him entangled in a Thicket by its horns
and Abraham went and took the lamb and
offered it up for a burnt offering
instead of his son so then so then what
I want you to understand stand here is
that
Abraham not only believed in a miracle
birth but he also believed as the knife
is coming down
Abraham believes that even though his
son is about to die that this is the
same son that will bring forth a great
multitude meaning Abraham believed in
the
resurrection
power of
God Abraham believed in the listen
carefully in Isaac in his birth his
almost death and his resurrection
Abraham was counted righteous because he
believed in those two things the miracle
birth and then the death burial and
Resurrection it was a sign of faith God
says all right Abraham stop not now I
know now I
know that you believe now I
know that's right Clint something that
had never been done before now I know so
then when the Bible says that Abraham
was justified by faith he was justified
by faith in what in by faith yes in the
word of God but particularly in the
birth Life Death burial and Resurrection
of Jesus Christ he believed it and it
was counted to him for righteousness the
Bible says in the book of Hebrews 11:17
by faith Abraham when he was tried
offered up Isaac and he that received
the promises offered up his only
begotten son of whom it was said that in
Isaac shall thy seed be called notice
this accounting that God was able to
raise him up from the dead from whence
he also received him as a figure so do
y'all catch this the Bible literally is
telling us here that Abraham believed
that God would raise him up from the
dead Abraham believed in the death
burial and resurrection of Christ it was
a figure of the things to
come okay so now that we understand this
the Bible tells
us the Bible tells us in 1 Thessalonians
4:14 for if we believe that Jesus
died and rose again even so them also
would sleep in Jesus will God bring with
him this is a fundamental of
Faith the belief that Jesus died and
rose
again all right I'm I'm taking y'all
somewhere with this so please follow
this
carefully justif justification by faith
is the belief in the death burial and
resurrection of Jesus Christ you believe
and it is accounted to you for
righteousness because the belief is a
very powerful belief now notice with me
Romans chapter 5 verse 1 Romans chapter
5 verse 1 the Bible says therefore being
justified by faith we have peace with
God through our Lord Jesus Christ we are
justified by faith the text is telling
us verse two it says by whom also we
have access by faith into this grace
wherein you stand and rejoice in the
hope of the glory of God notice verse
five and hope maketh not ashamed because
the love of God is shed abroad in our
hearts by the Holy Ghost which is given
unto us so the Bible is telling us that
it is the love of God which is shed
abroad in our hearts given us by the
Holy Spirit we are justified by faith
and the love of God is shed abroad in
our hearts justification by faith has
very much to do with love the love of
God please keep that in mind now notice
the very next verse why it says that the
love of God is shed abroad in our hearts
verse six says for when we were yet
without strength in due time
Christ died for the ungodly Christ died
for the ungodly so
then we are justified by faith in the
belief that Christ died for the ungodly
and and in him dying for the ungodly
that is what sheds abroad the love of
God in our hearts because the
demonstration of love on the
cross in that Christ died Romans
5:7 for scarcely for a righteous man
will one die yet per adventure for a
good man some would even dare to die but
God commended his love toward us that
while we were yet sinners Christ died
for us much more than being now
justified by his blood we shall be saved
from wrath through him for if when we
were enemies we were reconciled to God
by the death of his son much more being
reconciled we shall be saved by his life
okay I just read a whole lot there let
me break it down for you the Bible says
in verse 9 much more than being now
justified by his blood meaning we are
justified by his act of shedding his
blood of dying for us watch this we are
justified by his blood and saved from
wrath through him so there are two
things I want you to note here in Romans
chapter 5 and verse 9 those two things
are these number one Romans 5:9 talks
about being justified by his blood that
is his death and being saved from wrath
justified by his blood saved from his
wrath meaning justified by his
death saved from
wrath
okay beloved this is why it is so
important for us to Behold the Lamb of
God John 1:29 the next day John sees
Jesus and says Behold the Lamb of God
which taketh away the sin of the world
in the birth of Isaac in the almost
death of Isaac and the belief that he
would be resurrected we are beholding
the Lamb of God who who who came into
this
world as a baby through a miracle
birth was offered up for our
justification to save us from wrath
there it is right there that's the
gospel right there so so what we're
going to do beloved is we're going to
first focus on his justifi what does it
mean to be justified by his blood and
then we're going to focus on the Wrath
so let's break this down let's break
this
down justification by faith is the
belief that Jesus died for us that's
what it means when it says he shed his
blood that he died for us now are
you'all ready for the bombshell listen
carefully to
me it is crucial therefore to understand
what death is is if we're going to
appreciate what justification by faith
means if justification by faith is the
fact that Christ died for us then we
must understand what death is because
listen to me if we do not understand
what death is then we do not know what
Christ paid put a in the chat if that
makes sense to you just now put a one in
the chat if what I just said makes sense
to you put a two in the chat if you need
me to say it
again if justification by faith is the
fact that Christ died for us and
believing that he
died then if we don't if we do not know
what death
is it is impossible for us to understand
who the slides praise God to understand
what he paid on the cross for
us all
right
okay here we
go Joanne I'm going to explain that
again let's let's let's come back let's
come back
in order for us to understand and
appreciate justification by
faith because justification by faith is
pointing to the death of Christ if we
don't understand that
Christ died then we will not understand
the price Jesus Paid for us and if we
don't understand the price Jesus Paid
for us that throws everything off
because it is the foundation and the
centerpiece of the
gospel and you will see how this works
in a moment pray praise God why I need
y'all to catch this okay so so watch
this the question then is what does it
mean that Jesus died what does it mean
that Jesus Paid the penalty of death for
our sins what does it mean that Jesus
died okay let's go back to the screen
Genesis 2:1 17
Genesis 2:17 God speaking here tells
Adam and Eve but of the tree of the
knowledge of Good and Evil Thou shalt
not eat of it for the for in the day
thou eatest thereof Thou shalt surely
die Thou shalt surely die so the
question then becomes what is death when
ad when God said to Adam you will surely
die Follow Me
Now whatever that meant to Adam and Eve
is what Jesus would come to
pay put a one in the chat if that makes
sense everyone whatever death
was to Adam and Eve that was the thing
that Jesus was coming to pay and so now
we got to ask ourselves a question when
Adam and Eve died did they go to heaven
did they did they die and just not
really die but just transitioned into
another form of life because that's what
that's that's a very popular belief
within Christianity that you don't
really die you just trans you just you
just move from one form of life into
another form of
life so the question is whatever
happened to Adam and Eve whatever death
is it is the thing that happened to Adam
and Eve and it is the thing that Jesus
was coming to
pay are y'all with me so far so let's
continue to break this down what how
does God describe death to Adam and Eve
after they eat of the tree notice with
me in Genesis CH 2:7 the Bible says and
the Lord God formed man of the Dust of
the ground and breathed into his
nostrils the breath of life and Man
became a living Soul so where does man
come from man came from the dust of the
ground man is dust notice why this is so
important because after Adam and Eve sin
the Bible says God speaking to them in
the sweat of thy face shalt thou eat
bread till thou return unto the ground
for out of it thou was taken for dust
you are and unto dust shalt thou return
what is death according to Genesis 3:
19 it is
returning to the
ground that's what death is death is
going into the ground
for a man that is what death is for Adam
and Eve death was a return to the
dust this is significant because we know
that according to Isaiah 53:6 the Bible
says all we like sheep have gone astray
we have turned everyone to his own way
and the lord has laid on him that is
Jesus the iniquity of us all in other
words the sentence that was pronounced
upon Adam and Eve because of their
iniquity is laid upon
Christ all right are y'all following me
that sentence that was directed to Adam
and Eve has now been taken has been
placed upon Christ okay so so why is
this significant please follow along
with me job
34:14 if he said set his heart upon man
if he gather unto himself his spirit and
his breath All Flesh Shall Perish
together and man shall turn again unto
dust okay how about Isaiah 26:19 thy
dead men shall live together with my
dead body shall they arise awake and
sing ye that dwell in the dust for thy
doe is as a do of the herbs and the
Earth shall cast out her dead I need you
to understand here that death is simply
a return to the ground death is simply a
dwelling in the dust that's what the
Bible tells us when Adam and Eve died
they went back into the ground they went
back into the Earth let's keep reading
Ezekiel 12:7 notice with me then shall
the dust return to the Earth as it was
and the spirit shall return unto God who
gave it how about Psalm 10429 thou
howest thy face they are trouble Tred
thou takest away thy breath they die and
return to their dust all right come on
let's keep going y'all job 17:16 they
shall go down to the bars of the pit
when our rest together together is in
the dust job here says listen everyone
who dies is resting together in the dust
so what I want you to understand here is
a very simple equation
man is dust
man is dust in fact Psalm 103:14 the
Bible says here notice with me for he
knoweth our frame he
rememberthe are but what what are we
everyone put it in the chat for me we
are what we are
dust man is but dust now why is this
significant because in in Philippians
chap 2:6 speaking of Jesus who was
God who is God the Bible says who being
in the form of God thought it not
robbery to be equal with God but made
himself of no reputation and took upon
him the form of a servant and was made
in the likeness
of I need y'all to catch
this the god of the universe became dust
like
us
do I need to say that again the god of
the universe became dust like us you
could say just like us but I'm saying
dust like
us the god of the universe became just
like us just like us to take on the
penalty of sin to die in our place now
now there are two beles about death and
and here's what I want you to understand
in this message today I'm not going
through a whole explanation of you know
a whole Bible study what happens when a
person dies because what we're talking
about is the doctrine of justification
by faith and why this is so crucial to
understanding what really happens when a
person dies and what happens in the in
in the in the punishment of the wicked
this all ties in so it's not going to be
that type of a study follow along there
are two beliefs about death one is
biblical and one is a perversion of what
death is so if we if we grab on to the
perversion of what death is
then we lack the understanding do y'all
catch what I'm saying if justification
by faith is about the mindblowing fact
that Jesus died for us and if we have
the wrong definition of what death is
then we will will by Nature not
understand the
value of being justified by faith we
don't understand what it is because we
don't understand the value we don't
understand what death is therefore we
don't understand what Jesus did on our
behalf we don't believe that we believe
something
else absolutely there cannot be a real
appreciation for what he suffered so
what of the two belie about death here
they are number one is that death is
actually
death number two the other belief is
that death doesn't really
exist one
belief is that death is a real thing the
other belief is that death is not so
it's you know it's a
transition into another form of life
which means it's not really
death are y are yall understanding what
I'm saying so some people will even say
oh yeah you know the the body dies but
the soul lives on no no no let's just
move that out the way real quick notice
with me Ezekiel 18:4 behold All Souls
are mine the soul of the father as the
soul of the father so also the soul of
the son the soul that sinth it shall die
so we now know that Souls die that's a
Biblical truth y'all it's right there in
the text the soul that sinth it shall
die Ezekiel 18:20 the same thing the
soul that sinth it shall die the son
shall not bear the iniquity of the
father neither shall the father bear the
iniquity of the son the righteous of the
of his righteousness shall be upon him
the wickedness of his wickedness shall
be upon Him Matthew 10:28 fear not them
which kill the body but are not able to
kill the soul but rather fear Him that
is able to destroy or kill both body and
soul in hell so what I'm saying beloved
is that in death there is no
separation when a person dies they
either die or they're it's one of two
options either the person is dead or the
person is
not and for many many people believe
that that Jesus didn't really die he
just went back to where he came
from he just moved from being in this
form of life to being another form of
life so in fact there was really no
death I mean yeah we call it death but
it wasn't really dead it wasn't really
death and thus Beloved the sacrifice of
Christ is minimized when we teach when
we believe that Christ didn't really die
he just just went back home he was just
like Hey listen y'all uh I'm about to
get beat and by the way do you realize
that that's why for so many Christians
the the what they focus on is the
beating up of Christ that was the bad
part and then when he dies you know ah
now he's good hey he's dead he's back
home it's the beating
up so really it should be so God so
loved the world that he gave his only
begotten son to be beaten up that
whosoever believeth in him should not
perish but have everlasting life no
beloved that's not the S the sacrifice
the the the trial wasn't oh look how bad
he was beaten up the trial is that he
actually died for us see most many
people believe John 2017 look at what
they believe let me show it to you John
20:1 17 Jesus saith unto her touch me
not for I have not yet ascendant to my
father but go to my brethren and say
unto them I shall Ascend I Ascend unto
my father and your father to my God and
your God so watch this
the text is telling us here that 3 days
after Jesus's death he had not yet gone
to heaven so now we can know for sure
that when Jesus Jesus did not
transition from being on a cross to okay
now I'm about to go to heaven I'm in
heaven I I'm just living in a new form
that's not what
happened
so if Jesus did not go to
heaven if he was not in heaven for those
three
days where was
he come on let's go back to the screen
Psalm 16:10 a Messianic Psalm says this
for thou wil not leave my soul in Hell
neither will thou suffer thine Holy One
to see
corruption you see love there's a
reason why why
Jes where if he was not in
heaven where was
he this word for hell signifies the
grave he was right where God said to
Adam and Eve out of the ground you came
you are dust dust you shall return to
Jesus Took the sentence that was given
to Adam and Eve and he was in the grave
for three days and three he was in the
earth in the belly of the earth not in
heaven not in a burning place called
hell he was in the
grave in fact in Matthew 28:5 notice
what the Bible says here Matthew 28:5
the Angel answered and said unto the
woman fear not for I know that you seek
Jesus which was crucified he is not
here for He Is Risen come see the place
where the Lord lay now let's break this
down y'all what do the Angels mean he is
not
here he is not here would be the
opposite or he is not
here means he is risen so if he was not
risen then where would he be
come on y'all put the word in the chat
if he is not here why because he is
risen then if he was not risen he would
be
here where is
here it was the
tomb so now we understand that for those
three days Jesus was in the
Tomb not in heaven not in a burning
place he was in the
Tomb the Bible tells us in Romans
chapter 6 verse 23 for the wages of sin
is death but the gift of God is eternal
life through Jesus Christ if the wages
of sin is death but Jesus didn't really
die come on y'all let's break this down
let's break this down what is sin
what is
sin sin is the transgression of the
law so if sin is the transgression of
the law and Jesus had to die because of
sin the transgress of the law then if
Jesus actually died which means he went
to the grave and ceased to
exist for three days he was asleep in
the ground for three days that's
huge that is what transgression of the
law led
to Jesus ceasing to know to exist for
three
days now see if I believe that
Jesus when he died was actually just
transitioning all of a sudden
now
not a big deal I mean yeah you know hey
I can't wait to die either cuz then I go
straight to heaven not a big
deal hey death is you know it's
cool we just we just die and go right to
Heaven that's a
reward Jesus got
rewarded he didn't so that's again this
is why in many of the when many people
those who believe this they look at the
beating up of Jesus on the cross as of
more significance than his death because
they don't see his death as death and if
you don't see his death as death then
you cannot appreciate the law that put
him in the ground did y'all catch that
just
now you cannot appreciate the when you
minimize the death of Christ by teaching
that he didn't really
die you will also end up minimizing the
law that put him
there what was the state of Jesus what
was the state of Jesus when when he died
the Bible tells us the Bible tells us
let's see if I can find it
here I'll just quote it it's Ezekiel 9:5
the living know that they shall die but
the dead know not
anything the Dead dead know not
anything Jesus when he was in the grave
came to a place where he knew not
anything and when you understand wait
wait a minute you mean Jesus was willing
to cease to exist Kayla thank
you thank you this morning I I am giving
you the credit with the holy spirit that
gave that Jesus was willing to cease to
exist to become nothing to nothing for
me there is something about
that that Sparks a loving response in
the heart where you're like he did that
for me not oh he went home for
me you see you can act like oh he went
home for me is a really big deal but
seriously think about that all right
y'all I'm about to go back home right
now so I'm on the cross yeah they beat
me up that was a bad part but now I'm
about to go back to Heaven
peace no beloved no no no that's not
what happened the the the the the the
amazing thing about Jesus is that he was
willing to die to cease to go into a
state of
nonexistence on our
behalf I so don't want to be without you
that I am willing to go into
non-existence to give you a chance to be
saved it's very interesting it's very
interesting do you know what Muslims
teach about the death of
Jesus do you know what Muslims teach
about the death of
Jesus
they teach that Jesus didn't really
die that that there was a veil put over
somebody else that made the person look
like Jesus but it wasn't really Jesus
now we understand we understand that
that is Satan's attempt in the
non-Christian world to to remove the
idea that Jesus
died but there's a Christian version to
that
and the Christian version was introduced
when when when the serpent said in the
garden you shall not surely
die so the Christian version is that
yeah you know Jesus he his body died but
you know like he wasn't really he just
went straight back to Heaven he didn't
sleep in the ground he wasn't he just
transitioned from one form of existence
to another
and beloved when we do that we may as
well be doing what the Muslim said which
is he didn't really die it's just a
different
form justification by faith in his death
requires us to understand what death is
so that we then have an
appreciation of what he did for of the
actual sacrifice we now know what he
paid and when we now know what he paid
there is a love that is produced in the
heart that will lead us to Value what
Jesus says to Value when he says if you
love me keep my
Commandments we understand man the s
that law put him to death well if that
law put him to death what will it do to
me we understand okay so if he could
have gotten rid of the law he would have
done that before he died so that he
wouldn't have to die but he died to show
the unchangeable nature of the law and
beloved all of this becomes so crucial
when we're trying to understand what it
means when we're justified in the belief
that Jesus actually died for
us so then watch this the first thing
that the enemy seeks to do is to
minimize the death of Jesus why because
in minimizing the death of Jesus what he
ends up doing is he minimizes
justification by faith and makes it a a
a a mockery of what the doctrine
actually
is how does he do this follow along
we're moving to our second portion of
this message of this study listen
carefully so remember what we just saw
right Romans 5 and verse 9 where the
Bible says much more than being now
justified by his blood that is by faith
belief that
Jesus
died not
transitioned
died so so remember much more than being
justified by his blood we shall be saved
from wrath through him so there are two
things here first justified by his death
and then saved from his wrath now let's
talk about the Wrath we just talked
about the death right we just basically
said listen it is important for us to
understand what death is because when we
adopt the idea of death promoted by
Satan in the garden which is you shall
not really die you are Eternal you don't
die your soul is naturally Immortal when
we adopt that view what it says to us is
that Jesus didn't really
die you don't really die nobody really
dies we just transition
from one state of living to another
state of
living one form of living to another
form there is no such really no such
thing as actual death
cessation what is this wrath in Isaiah
13:9 notice with me behold the day of
the Lord cometh cruel both with wrath
and fierce anger to lay the land
desolate and he shall destroy the
Sinners thereof out of it so now we see
that
wrath is against
Sinners what do Sinners do what do
Sinners do put it in the chat y'all
Sinners it's right there in the word
Sinners
sin okay sin or sin pretty simple pretty
straightforward Pastor what is sin sin
is
transgression 1 John 3:4 whosoever
committed sin transgresses also of the
law for sin is the
transgression of the
law so then we are
Justified we are justified by his blood
meaning forgiven for our transgression
of the law but those who reject his
justification must face wrath which is
against Sinners transgression of the law
so we see that there's this idea of the
transgression of the law on both sides
of the question of justification by
faith and watch what the devil does on
the one hand he minimizes the idea of
death so that justification by faith is
minimized the importance of it the
significance of it is
minimized on the other hand the devil
wants to
magnify the wrath of God so watch this
y'all on one one hand he minimizes death
oh you don't really die and on the other
hand he
magnifies what the wrath of God actually
is watch watch Revelation 14:10 the
Bible says the same shall drink of the
wrath of God which is poured out without
mixture into the cup of his indignation
and he shall be tormented with fire and
brimstone in the presence of the Holy
Angels and in the presence of the Lamb
all right so when we talk about the
Wrath this is what it is the wrath of
God against Sinners is the destruction
of the wicked by
fire
now if you don't really
die if you don't really
die then the
natural belief about the wrath of God is
that the Wrath is an eternal wrath
meaning if death doesn't really
exist then when you transition cuz
that's all it is when you
transition and if you haven't believed
in Jesus you're transitioning into
hell and where will you be for all
eternity you will be burning in Hell
forever because there's really no such
thing as death in Hell you'll be alive
forever and in Hell you'll be tormented
alive forever in
hell so since Jesus didn't really die
and we don't really die then the wrath
of God is eternal because the soul is
Immortal and again there's then really
no such thing as death however beloved
praise God we have the
Bible because the Bible says in Malachi
4:3 you shall tread down the wicked for
they shall be ashes under the soul of
your feet in the day that I shall do
this say the Lord the Bible tells us
clearly that the wicked will become
ashes why does the bible described the
wicked as being cast into Everlasting
fire it is because Jesus is that
Everlasting fire God is that ever the
wicked are not Everlasting it is God who
is Everlasting and since the Bible says
our God is a consuming fire he is that
eternal flame in fact in fact we just
read a little bit earlier that the
wicked will will will be tormented in
the presence of the Lamb I need y'all to
understand this where is the presence of
the lamb for all eternity put it in the
chat for me please where is the presence
of the lamb for all
eternity the presence of the Lamb let's
just put it up on the screen Revelation
21:23 and the city had no need of the
sun neither of the moon to shine in it
for the glory of God did lighten it and
the lamb is the light thereof where is
the Lamb for all eternity where is the
Lamb he's in the New
Jerusalem so then please think about
this if the wicked are tormented in the
presence of the lamb and supposedly so
for all eternity where does that put the
wicked for all eternity it puts them in
the New Jerusalem and we know that
that's not
biblical so wherever the wicked are
destroyed it's not in the New Jerusalem
and whatever that destruction is it must
come to an end because the lamb will
spend eternity in the New Jerusalem in
the new
Earth
again Note 1 John chapter 3:15 the Bible
says whosoever hateth his brother is a
murderer and you know that no murderer
has what eternal life abiding in
him in order to burn forever you must
live forever but if no Wicked person has
eternal life abiding in them then it is
impossible for them to burn forever did
y'all catch what I just said in order to
burn forever you must live forever
meaning you must have the belief about
death that death does not really exist
it is really just a transition it's not
death and if you believe that death
doesn't really exist then you cannot
also believe that Jesus actually died he
just transition and if Jesus didn't die
then your justification by faith is is
is a mute point you don't understand it
you don't this is why Beloved the devil
is so intent on minimizing death and
maximizing
wrath because you see if he can maximize
Wrath in your mind what I need you to
understand is that what this produces
when you believe that God will burn the
wicked forever and ever and ever and
ever and ever is that this Doctrine
produces fear put that word in the chat
for
me because if God is going to punish
someone for a finite amount of
crime
using Infinity then that is not
just if the Bible says God is love but
he's willing to torment forever that is
not love if the Bible says God is
merciful but he's willing to torment
forever that is not merciful and so what
happens is our picture of God becomes
one of a picture of a
tyrant but hey I don't want to tick off
the
Tyrant
so are y'all catching this so I'm going
to worship God I am because I'd rather
worship God than Burn For
Eternity beloved note this Revelation
20:3 the Bible says the this is at the
end of the 1,000 years the Bible says
and the Sea gave up the dead which were
in it and death and Hell delivered up
the dead which were in them and they
were judged every man according to their
works and death and hell were cast into
the Lake of Fire this is the second
death okay y'all if F if the lake if if
people are burning right now in hell
what sense would it make for God to take
people out of hell and cast them into a
lake out of a burning place and cast
them into a burning Lake of Fire at the
end of the 10,000 years that would make
literally no sense what I'm trying to
demonstrate to you is that there's no
place of Hell burning right now it will
happen but it doesn't happen until the
end of what Revelation calls the 1,000
years this is the second death and it's
not called the second torment it's
called the second death and what is
death death is the cessation of life
meaning if you're dead you cannot also
be
alive you are either dead or either
alive Jesus Jesus was dead for 3 days
but now he is alive if you and I were
alive back then when Jesus died on that
Friday night we would not say be saying
Jesus is Alive that would destroy the
Christian
message if Jesus goes like this on the
cross and then and now we're like he's
alive praise God that would destroy the
Christian
message so we know that we would have
said Jesus is dead and three days later
we could say ah now Jesus is Alive he is
alive now he was not alive then and how
do we know he was alive because there
was an empty tomb an empty tomb proves
that Jesus was alive a fill tomb proed
that Jesus was dead so imagine the Roman
soldiers coming and seeing the body of
Jesus and going ah you know he's dead
and the disciples are like no he's
really alive his body is here but he's
really alive Christianity would have
gone nowhere and yet we do that all day
this day persons dead we're like oh well
they're alive now we deny death and if
we deny death then we cannot rightly
appreciate justification by faith in the
fact that Jesus died for us because now
we're saying he didn't really die I mean
yeah you could say he died but he didn't
really
die this produces fear when we see
eternally burning hell what happens is
that we now begin to fear but the Bible
says Beloved the Bible says in first Tim
2 Timothy 1:7 For God is not given us
the spirit of fear but of power and of
love and of a sound mind Romans 8:15
says for you have not received the
spirit of bondage again to fear but have
received the spirit of adoption whereby
we cry ABA father so here's what I want
you to understand y'all let me put this
up on the screen do y'all see this note
again that I had put in my title
justification by faith justification by
faith but what this Doctrine does is it
produces justification by
fear
justification by fear and what I need
y'all to understand beloved is that when
you're motivated by fear come back come
back when you're motivated by fear when
you're motivated by fear and I'm just
not I'm just noticing I got jfb it
should be
jbf so don't mind that when you're
motivated by
fear What Fear does is it produces a
minimalistic approach to
Salvation because now I am so
overwhelmed with fear I'm not truly
interested in serving you I just want to
know what is the least thing I can do or
say to be determined as saved ah just
believe cool cool just believe if if
that's what needs to happen for me to
avoid the fires of just believe okay
cool I don't want to hear anything else
because I don't really love you listen I
don't really I'm afraid of the fire
because because to torment anybody
forever is totally but I can't say that
cuz I don't want to end up in a fire so
I Love You Lord and I lift my hands
don't burn
me don't kill me cuz I don't want to go
to y' y'all catch
it it's fake obedience because it's
motivated out of a fear of since we
don't die and since God will actually
punish us throughout all eternity then
whatever it takes for me to be to for
not whatever what is the minimal amount
that I can that I can do to save myself
from that oh just believe got it
obedience n obedience is for people that
actually love you I'm not I I'm just
trying to avoid
hell did y'all catch
that James 2:19 watch this thou
believest there is one God thou doest
well the Devils also believe and tremble
but will thou know oh vain man that
faith without works is
dead
in a sense yes it is about belief but
belief in
what belief in what notice with me 1
Corinthians chapter 15: 3 and 4 we're
almost done y'all we're almost done
notice what the Bible says here for I
delivered unto you first of all that
which I also received how that Christ
died for our sins according to the
scriptures and that he was buried and
and that he rose again the third day let
me read that again and that he rose
again the first day is that what the
text
says did Jesus rise again the first day
did Jesus die and die and then just go
to heaven the first day remember you
know most most people say hey Jesus said
on the cross to the thief today you will
be with me in Paradise so what people
really believe is that Jesus rose again
the first day not the third day he rose
the first day he was already in heaven
he had already risen to Heaven he went
to heaven that day and if you believe
that he went to heaven that day you do
not believe that he rose again on the
third day yeah you might believe that
the shell of his body oh that happened
to come up on the third day but he
didn't
die he didn't actually die but let me I
need I need you to I need to break this
down for you that word rose again in in
1 Corinthians 15:4 rose again look at it
here it is it is the word airo listen to
this y'all here's the meaning of the
word in the Strong's Concordance through
the idea of collecting one's faculty to
waken that is rouse literally from sleep
from sitting or lying from disease from
Death or figura figuratively from
obscurity inactivity
ruins
nonexistence wow awake lift up raise RAR
up rise up stand take up do y'all see
this if you believe that Jesus rose
again on the third day so in other words
listen it could have been God could have
made it that Jesus died and rose again
the first day why does he make it three
days so that we can understand that
Jesus was actually
dead what is death it is to sleep in the
ground what has the devil done he wasn't
really dead and you don't really die and
if he wasn't really dead then you don't
understand justification by faith
because now if he wasn't really dead you
don't understand justification by faith
and you believe that the wicked are
tormented forever so now you're serving
God out of fear versus out of love the
Bible says in 1 John 4:17 Jesus said
unto him I'm I'm sorry 1 John 4:17 heing
is our love made perfect that we may
have boldness in the day of judgment
because as he is so are we in this world
there is no fear in love but perfect
love cast out fear because fear has
torment he that
feareth is not made perfect in love do
y'all see
this if the devil can get us to be
afraid of the character of God then
whatever service we're giving him is not
out of love it is out of fear and if
it's out of
fear if it's out of
fear if it's out of fear it's not out of
love see the text we just read said that
we may have boldness in the day of
judgment do you want to know why so many
people so many Christians are afraid of
the idea of
judgment it's because they're afraid of
the idea of hell
because if hell is really what it is I
don't even want to have a discussion
about
judgment if if I can just get away with
wait just believe all right I believe I
said it with my mouth I believe don't
tell me
about I just if I can just claim that I
believe and that's all that I need to
do cuz see I'm just trying to survive so
tell me what I need to do to escape this
situation oh just say okay cool I say I
believe I got you justification by faith
got it I believe justify me I
believe you become afraid of judgment
because you don't understand that Jesus
died that he
actually died and if you don't
understand the depth of what Jesus went
the depths to which Jesus went to to
save us I will cease to exist that you
might have a chance to exist if you
don't understand the price that was paid
then you minimize the idea of
justification by faith you minimize the
law that put Jesus in the grave you
minimize the reason Jesus came and and
you and you end up magnifying the
punishment because if no one dies the
punishment of sin is eternal life not
Eternal death but eternal life in hell
and that eternal life in hell produces
fear and now here here is the verse all
of this builds up to this verse
y'all all of this comes to this watch
this Galatians 56 full circle here we go
for in Jesus Christ neither circumcision
aileth anything nor uncircumcision but
Faith which
worketh
by
what
okay let's come back for a moment
to be justified you have to use what
what is the tool that we need to be
justified give give me the word the tool
that we need to be
justified the tool that we need to be
justified we have to be justified not by
works but
by
faith right by faith but how does faith
work how does faith work how do we have
a working
faith we have a working
Faith come on Faith Works by
love so now how do we get love here's
how we get Love by looking and saying
wow look at how beautiful Jesus God is
he burns the wicked forever and ever and
ever I love you God man ah I love you
God I love you look at that
you you mean for the sins that a person
did over 20 30 years they burned forever
in Hell God I love
you I love you and I want to be
justified by faith because if that's the
love if that
yeah so so then watch this when Jesus
now says hey if you love me keep my
Commandments it's like who
whoa whoa hold on hold
on no I just your word says you know I'm
justified by faith if I if I believe
that you died but I know you didn't
really die but the bottom line is nobody
really dies everybody lives forever and
I don't want to go to hell so yeah I
believe but don't ask me to keep your
Commandments is cuz that's motivated by
love and I but I do sing that I love
you yeah and I do say I love you oh yeah
and I
oh you see beloved when we behold the
cross and we allow the devil to get in
there and and alter the
picture to say yeah I see him on the
cross here he didn't really die so he
didn't really really died like what was
a big
deal he just went back to Heaven what
was a big deal what was the real
sacrifice if he just went back to Heaven
if he just transitioned to another place
by the way the wicked burn forever so
his death minimized his wrath
maximized and what does it
produce it
produces a lack of understanding of what
justification by faith is
because we don't even because you don't
even really believe Jesus died and then
to to to to to follow up on
that God is a tyrant because he he he
burns the wicked
forever I don't want
that I'm afraid of that kind of
God so yes I will sing to you but I'm
singing to you out of fear yes I will
say I love you but I I only love you out
of fear
yes I will say I give my life to you but
it is be it is not because I am moved by
the sacrifice of the cross it is because
I'm moved by the fear of the
fire you see if I understood what
actually happened on the cross I would
be moved by what happened at the cross
and I would begin to see correctly what
happens with the fire no it is not
Eternal Jesus didn't suffer eternally
for us listen to me y'all if the wages
of sin
is not death but eternal torment Jesus
never paid those wages and if Jesus
didn't pay the wages of our sin then we
are all lost let me say it
again if the wages of sin is eternal
torment and not death which are two
different
things Jesus was not tormented eternally
meaning he did not pay those wages he
was only dead for three days and if he
was only dead for three days and not
being tormented to this day he has not
paid the penalty for our sins and if he
has not paid the penalty for our sins
then we are all
lost
beloved
Jesus died for
you now I know it just s you know how
often we Jesus died for you but I need
you to understand there's so many people
out in the world who have taken that
statement and do not know what it
means Jesus died for you if if we can
just if we can get that wait a minute
wait a minute wa wait you mean Jesus
didn't transition into another form of
life he
actually
died you mean like died
died and beloved that changes everything
that is why the devil is so intent on
attacking this doctrine of what happens
when you
die that's
why if I can minimize what death is then
I have minimized the price Jesus Paid on
Calvary beloved that's it that's that's
what I have for
you I is my
prayer you know we can go through this
study and I could I could have pulled
out 50 verses on on Hellfire and why
it's this way and not that way 50 verses
on the state of the dead but we're not
doing that today today I'm I'm simply
showing you how the devil has taken
these two doctrines and how the correct
understanding of justif a by faith fixes
how we see death and how we see the
punishment of the
wicked and is my prayer today that if
you're if you're watching this and
you're hearing this for the first time
that you will in fact come to believe
that
Jesus
actually died for
you let's pray Heavenly
Father you sent sent your son into this
world not on a round trip ticket to just
come here and then and then catch a ride
back at the cross no no no no no you
sent your son into this world to die for
us and he was
dead and so many people deny this
truth so many people have watered down
this truth he didn't really die he went
back to on the first day it's not that
he they say he rules yes yes bodily he
came back but he wasn't dead no one
dies please
Lord may this truth become a
reality in the minds and hearts of
people people who you are seeking to
save and draw to
you and may we understand Lord that you
are not a tyrant the devil takes
doctrines and flips them in ways that
make people afraid of you instead of
Loving You Lord please help us to see
your true character and as a
result may we fall in love with you not
in fear with you but in love with you is
our prayer in Jesus name
amen